Matt Prestlien

+1 (360) 303-6901 mprestlien@me.com http://mattprestlien.com/

Bellingham, WA 98225

Profile

Professional, and versatile engineer hailing from a veteran SaaS firm. Experience and acute interest in mobile web app development, specifically with AngularJS and Cordova. Works proficiently alone and adeptly within group or team dynamics. Dedicated work ethic, coupled with excellent time management skills and attention to detail.

Experience

Software Engineer, ServiceMonster; Bellingham, WA - 2014-Present

Tasked with translating an <u>ASP.net</u> application to a mobile app, I chose frameworks and technologies carefully to ensure that the product could be built rapidly and efficiently. Identified features that were important to customers, and defined new functionality while still ensuring an intuitive end-user experience. As the sole engineer working on the project (ServiceMonster Mobile), I was required to constantly prioritize different tasks and collaborate with my peers in every different part of the company, later on including hiring and training team members, as well as deploying developer support software such as GitLab and Sentry via Docker.

Apple Service Specialist, CityMac; Bellingham, WA - 2012-2014

Began work as a trainer, working with customers to teach them about their computers, tablets, and phones. Attained knowledge of explaining complex technology topics in layman's terms, which has served me well working with my engineering colleagues. Spent time as a technician solving customer issues and completing repairs, ultimately resulting in creating an imaging server to speed up refurbishing.

Office Assistant, Heininger Holdings; Bellingham, WA - 2009-2010

Education

Associate in Liberal Studies

Whatcom Community College, Bellingham, WA; Running Start 2012-2015

Began Running Start in 2012, took a variety of courses seeking to expand upon concepts I had been introduced to in high school. Performed to a high standard in my science and programming courses; receiving positive reviews and a recommendation from the faculty.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks

A very strong IT background has contributed greatly to my problem-solving skills and engineering process. I have worked in Objective-C and Swift on a few small projects. More recently, I have gained a deep understanding of AngularJS via the Ionic framework, building services and plugins to support a line-of-business application.

Communication

Work methodically with a team of individuals in order to achieve a common goal. Current employment involves managing a small team and making design decisions with according to stakeholder input. Personal projects include managing dedicated servers for video games, and also the communities that surround them in order to ensure everyone has a positive experience.

Technologies

- AngularJS
- Cordova
- Ionic

- ES6
- NodeJS
- Gulp

- Docker
- GitLab/GitLab Cl
- Sentry/Rollbar